<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sandslamsal.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://sandslamsal.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-16T23:02:47+00:00</updated><id>https://sandslamsal.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Presenting at ASCE Earth and Science 2024: A Look into SEAHIVE Breakwaters</title><link href="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2024/ASCE-Earth-and-Space-2024/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presenting at ASCE Earth and Science 2024: A Look into SEAHIVE Breakwaters"/><published>2024-04-17T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-17T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2024/ASCE-Earth-and-Space-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2024/ASCE-Earth-and-Space-2024/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Presenting at the ASCE Earth and Science 2024: Insights into Spatial Arrangement of SEAHIVE® Breakwaters</strong></p> <hr/> <p><strong>Author:</strong> Sandesh Lamsal, Ph.D. Student, Civil and Architectural Engineering, University of Miami</p> <p><strong>Advisors:</strong> Dr. Landolf Rhode-Barbarigos, Dr. Brian Haus</p> <hr/> <h2 id="overview">Overview</h2> <p>Yesterday, I had the privilege of presenting our latest research on “A Sustainable and Efficient Structural Solution for Hybrid Coral Reefs” at the ASCE Earth and Science 2024 conference. This presentation focused on the innovative SEAHIVE® system—a shoreline-protection strategy that combines hexagonal concrete prisms to dissipate wave energy and support marine habitats.</p> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/asce2024-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/asce2024-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/asce2024-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/asce2024.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <p><em>Presenting SEAHIVE® configurations at the conference</em></p> <h2 id="research-highlights">Research Highlights</h2> <p>Our study assesses the protective performance of both solid and perforated SEAHIVE® structures in mitigating wave impacts. We’ve conducted extensive scaled testing at the University of Miami’s Alfred C. Glassell Jr. SUSTAIN Laboratory to understand how these structures can best serve coastal defense while promoting ecological growth.</p> <h2 id="key-findings">Key Findings</h2> <ol> <li><strong>Energy Dissipation:</strong> Perforated SEAHIVE® units demonstrated up to 45% more energy dissipation compared to solid structures, providing significant protection with lower material use.</li> <li><strong>Ecological Benefits:</strong> The design encourages biodiversity, turning functional breakwaters into thriving marine habitats.</li> <li><strong>Design Flexibility:</strong> SEAHIVE® can be configured in various layouts to optimize protection based on local wave and water conditions.</li> </ol> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The positive reception to our presentation reaffirms the potential of SEAHIVE® technology in coastal engineering. The blend of functionality and sustainability addresses critical needs in shoreline protection and ecological preservation.</p> <p>I am grateful for the insightful discussions and feedback from the conference attendees, which will undoubtedly help refine our ongoing research.</p> ]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ASCE,"/><category term="Earth"/><category term="and"/><category term="Space,"/><category term="2024,"/><category term="Space"/><category term="Exploration,"/><category term="Earth"/><category term="Science"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Presenting at the ASCE Earth and Science 2024:Insights into Spatial Arrangement of SEAHIVE® Breakwater Structures.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hurricane Sandy Effects on Tottenville, NY, Natural Hazard Mitigation Planning using GIS Mapping</title><link href="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2023/Hurricane-Sandy-Effects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hurricane Sandy Effects on Tottenville, NY, Natural Hazard Mitigation Planning using GIS Mapping"/><published>2023-11-07T20:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-07T20:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2023/Hurricane-Sandy-Effects</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2023/Hurricane-Sandy-Effects/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Poster Presentation Competition Showcasing ‘Hurricane Sandy Effects on Tottenville, NY: Natural Hazard Mitigation Planning using GIS Mapping’ at the Celebratory Event of GIS Day 2023, Organized by the University of Miami</strong></p> <hr/> <p>Authors: Sandesh Lamsal, Kylee Rux, Abdullah Rahmatullah, Gustavo Aguilar</p> <h2 id="abstract">Abstract</h2> <p>In October 2012, one of the most destructive hurricanes in U.S. history made landfall, referred to as Superstorm Sandy. Tottenville, NY was exposed storm surge levels of 14 feet. Following the hurricane, a national competition was launched for climate change adaptation projects. One of the selected projects was the Staten Island Living Breakwaters Project. GIS mapping was applied to pre-storm and post-storm data to assess the impacts of Hurricane Sandy and to evaluate the benefits of implementing a breakwater structure. GIS maps offered valuable insights. Tottenville’s southeast coast, consisting of high home values and concentrations of buildings, experienced significant damage. Results concerning the socio-economic landscape revealed disparities in median household income. Additional GIS maps depicted the effectiveness of breakwater structures, highlighting the potential of breakwaters for coastal protection and climate resilience. Ultimately, GIS offered visual representations and played an essential role in assessing the effect of Hurricane Sandy.</p> <p><a href="https://miami.box.com/s/ej5oqnzstk385139dbrye8v4j6yj2fd9">Link to the Presentation Poster</a></p> <p><a href="https://sp.library.miami.edu/subjects/gis#tab-3">Link to the University of Miami page</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Hurricane"/><category term="Sandy,"/><category term="2023,"/><category term="Urban"/><category term="Development,"/><category term="Civil"/><category term="Engineering,"/><category term="Disaster"/><category term="Management"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A detailed analysis of the effects and aftermath of Hurricane Sandy, focusing on its impact on urban development and civil engineering practices.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Impact of HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation on Civil Engineering Education in Nepal</title><link href="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2017/HELVETAS-Swiss-Intercooperation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Impact of HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation on Civil Engineering Education in Nepal"/><published>2017-05-16T09:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-16T09:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2017/HELVETAS-Swiss-Intercooperation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2017/HELVETAS-Swiss-Intercooperation/"><![CDATA[<figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/helvetas-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/helvetas-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/helvetas-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/helvetas.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <p><em>Cable Sag Setting for suspended bridge at Panga, Kritipur, Kathmandu.</em></p> <p>In the final year of our Bachelor of Civil Engineering program in Nepal, we were fortunate to receive the support of HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation. This organization, dedicated to the development and implementation of projects that change the lives of people in developing countries, provided us with the necessary resources to complete our thesis project.</p> <p>Our project focused on the design of two different trail bridges in Nepal: a suspended bridge at Panga, Kritipur, and a suspension bridge at Madaiyatapanpur, Sarlahi. These bridges are not just structures; they are lifelines that connect communities, facilitate trade, and provide access to essential services like healthcare and education.</p> <p>HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation provided us with technical books, training, and the opportunity to visit the actual sites of these bridges. This hands-on experience was invaluable. It allowed us to understand the practical challenges that come with bridge construction in the diverse geographical and climatic conditions of Nepal.</p> <p>The bridges at Panga and Madaiyatapanpur are particularly important due to their locations. Panga, a historical town in the Kathmandu Valley, is a bustling hub of activity. The bridge here improves local transportation and supports the town’s economic activities. On the other hand, Madaiyatapanpur in Sarlahi, a district in the Terai plains, is a rural area where the bridge significantly enhances connectivity for the local farming communities.</p> <p>I would like to express my deepest gratitude to Er. Lal Jha from Bardibas for facilitating everything for the Sarlahi site, and to Mr. Netra Khanal for the Panga site. Their assistance and guidance were invaluable to our project. We are also immensely grateful to our supervisor, Sushil Kumar Bhandari, for providing us with all the necessary resources and for his continuous support throughout our project.</p> <p>Additionally, I would like to thank my teammates for their collaboration and hard work. This project would not have been possible without their dedication and commitment. We are proud of what we have achieved together and look forward to applying the knowledge and skills we have gained to future projects.</p> <p>In conclusion, the support from HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation was more than just financial. It was an opportunity for us to apply our theoretical knowledge in a real-world context, understand the socio-economic impact of our work, and contribute to the development of our country. We are grateful for this experience, which has shaped us as engineers and as individuals committed to the progress of Nepal.</p> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/panga-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/panga-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/panga-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/panga.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <p><em>The completed bridge, standing as a testament to successful construction (Photo courtesy of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/kirtipur.panga">Panga, Kirtipur</a>).</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects"/><category term="HELVETAS,"/><category term="Civil"/><category term="Engineering,"/><category term="Nepal,"/><category term="Bridge"/><category term="Design"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reflection on the invaluable support provided by HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation for our final year thesis in Bachelor of Civil Engineering.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revolutionizing Urban Parking, A Proposal for a Multi-Story Parking Building in Newroad, Nepal</title><link href="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2017/New-Road-Parking_Solution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revolutionizing Urban Parking, A Proposal for a Multi-Story Parking Building in Newroad, Nepal"/><published>2017-02-22T09:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-22T09:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2017/New-Road-Parking_Solution</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sandslamsal.github.io/blog/2017/New-Road-Parking_Solution/"><![CDATA[<figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/parking-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/parking-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/parking-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/parking.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <p><em>Photo of attendees from our college at the unveiling of the proposed parking building.</em></p> <p>At the 16th National Civil Engineering Cum held at IOE Pulchowk Campus, our team unveiled a groundbreaking proposal aimed at alleviating urban congestion and parking woes in Newroad, Nepal. With a strategic vision and meticulous planning, we introduced a design concept for a seven-story parking building situated near the Sukraraj Shastri statue, utilizing an open governmental plot area. Newroad, a bustling commercial hub in Nepal, grapples with severe traffic congestion and a scarcity of parking spaces. Recognizing the pressing need for a sustainable solution, our team embarked on a mission to revolutionize urban parking infrastructure. Our proposal entails the construction of a multi-story parking building to accommodate a significant number of vehicles efficiently. Through extensive traffic surveys and analysis, we meticulously evaluated the area’s traffic patterns and parking demands. The proposed seven-story structure was strategically designed to optimize space utilization while adhering to safety and regulatory standards. The structural integrity of the parking building was of paramount importance. Leveraging advanced engineering techniques, including Response Spectrum Analysis based on prevailing NBC and IS standards, our team devised a robust structural design capable of withstanding seismic forces and ensuring long-term durability. A comprehensive cost-benefit analysis underscored the economic viability and societal impact of our parking solution. By quantifying the projected benefits in terms of reduced traffic congestion, improved accessibility, and enhanced urban aesthetics, we demonstrated the immense value proposition of the proposed investment. Our success in conceptualizing and presenting this transformative parking solution would not have been possible without the invaluable guidance and support of key stakeholders. We extend our heartfelt gratitude to Er. Hemant Tiwari, our esteemed guidance and academic coordinator, whose mentorship was instrumental throughout the project. Special thanks are also due to the NCE-Robotics Club and CESS (Civil Engineering Students’ Society-NCE) for their unwavering support and encouragement. We were also fortunate to present our proposal to our esteemed ex-prime minister and renowned architect, Dr. Babu Ram Bhattarai, whose insights and feedback enriched our understanding and strengthened our resolve to contribute meaningfully to urban development in Nepal. In conclusion, our proposal for a multi-story parking building in Newroad embodies the spirit of innovation and proactive urban planning. By harnessing civil engineering expertise and collaborative efforts, we aspire to create tangible solutions that enhance the quality of life for residents and visitors alike. Together, let us pave the way for a more sustainable and vibrant urban future.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects"/><category term="Parking"/><category term="Building,"/><category term="Newroad,"/><category term="Nepal,"/><category term="Civil"/><category term="Engineering,"/><category term="Urban"/><category term="Development"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A comprehensive overview of the innovative parking solution presented at the 16th National Civil Engineering Cum at IOE Pulchowk Campus, designed to address urban congestion and parking challenges in Newroad, Nepal.]]></summary></entry></feed>